You can only push an innocent man so far
Man on a Ledge is a action, thriller, crime film directed by Asger Leth.
An ex-cop turned con threatens to jump to his
death from a Manhattan hotel rooftop.
The NYPD dispatch a female police psychologist to talk him down.
However, unbeknownst to the police on the scene, the suicide attempt
is a cover for the biggest diamond heist ever pulled.
Nick Cassidy, played by Sam Worthington.
Lydia Mercer, played by Elizabeth Banks.
Joey Cassidy, played by Jamie Bell.
Mike Ackerman, played by Anthony Mackie.
Jack Dougherty, played by Edward Burns.
Angie, played by Genesis Rodriguez.
Man on a Ledge is a 2012 American action thriller film directed by Asger Leth, starring Sam Worthington,
Jamie Bell, Elizabeth Banks, Edward Burns, Anthony Mackie, Genesis Rodriguez, and Ed Harris.
Filming took place in New York City on top of the Roosevelt Hotel.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics and
grossed $47 million against its $42 million budget.
In the film, a man using an alias stages a suicide attempt and
asks to speak with a specific police negotiator.
He is himself a disgraced police officer who was convicted of a
diamond theft, and seeks a way to clear his name.
His associates try to prove that the diamond was never stolen, and that the
"theft" was part of an insurance fraud scheme by the diamond's owner.
The film explores themes of new york city, deception,
rooftop, diamond heist, framed for a crime.
The tone is intense.